Guide to the Barney Rosset papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Subject Files, 1841-2011
  - Joan Mitchell
    - "Pat Albers Bio Chapters 5 & 6," 2008 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - "Photos Scanned," 2002 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - "Sketches Naumann Gallery," 2005 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - "Masao Miyashi," 1995-1996 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - "New Theatre Review," 1994-1995 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - "New York Quarterly--Linda Tieber," 1996 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "John Oakes," 1980s 2004 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "May umi Oda," 1976-1996 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - "Cleo Odzer"
    - "Correspondence and Goa Freaks," 1993-2004, (2 folders) (Box 29, Folder 6-7)
    - "Patpong Sisters," 1994-1997 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Kenzaburo OE
    - General, 2000-2007 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - "Assorted Correspondence MASTER," 1965-2007, (2 folders) (Box 29, Folder 10-11)
    - "Assorted Correspondence Original," 1965-2003, (2 folders) (Box 29, Folder 12-13)
    - "Correspondence and Articles," 1966-1997 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - "Editing Copy of 17," 1961 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - "Hiroshima Notes," 1981 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - "Japan," 1965-1970 2005-2006 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - "Manuscripts of J and 17," 1995-1996 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - "J. Nathan on OE," 1976 1994 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - "Jeremiah Nathan," 1994-1996 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - "Nathan/Rosset," 1965-1997 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - "Nobel Ceremony," 1977-2002 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - "Reviews, Articles, Speech," 1994-2005 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "Rouse Up," Undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - "Tatemi Sakai"
      - "Nathan Correspondence," 1985-1996 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - "Sakai, Rosset, Goldstein," 1987-1996, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
    - "Van Haute and Packet sent to OE," 1993 2003 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - "Plimpton," 2002-2006 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - "George Plimpton Obits/Articles," 2003-2004 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - "Praeger Correspondence," 1970-1986 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "Prix Formentor"
    - "Copies of Originals," 1961-1963 2002 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - "Files, Names," 1997-1999 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - "Int. Lit. Prize," 2007 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - "Master," 1961-1965 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - "Originals," 1961-1968 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - "Publishers--A. Asher, H. Braverman, K. Carroll," 1973-1986 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Publishing the New Novel, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - "Real Estate & Properties," 1958-1975 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - "Rosset on Beckett--On S.B.'s FILM (Tin House)," 2001 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - "B.L. Rosset, Sr.,"
    - General, 1918-1953, (2 folders) (Box 30, Folder 19-20)
    - "Edits," 1939-1954 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - "Funeral," 1954 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - "History," 1954-1968 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "Rosset Excerpt from a Journal," 1948-1952 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - "Rosset's Journal and Fiction Writings," 1940-1955 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - "B.Rosset Letters to Parents," 1948-1953 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - "Rosset's New School Fiction," 1951 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - "Rosset to Parents," 1942-1944 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - "Rosset on Pollock," 1950 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - "Rosset-Gruen Correspondence," 1953 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - "Rosset, Turner, Gruen Correspondence," 1953 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - "Rosset, Turner, Gruen MASTER," 1953 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - "Rosset Writing," 1948-2005 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - "Mary Rosset"
    - "Financials, Trust Agreements," 1954-1967 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - "Gift Tax, Condolences, Letters, Clippings," 1966-1979 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - "Trust Fund, etc." 1950-1991 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - "Trust, Grove Press Prospectus, Gift Tax," 1955-2007 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - "Ledig Rowohlt--Originals," 1964-1995 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - "Judith Schmidt"
    - "Correspondence--Master," 1956-1967 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - "Correspondence--Originals," 1956-1967, (2 folders) (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
  - "Richard Seaver," 1967-1989 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - "Shangai Fiction/Temporary Duty," 1945-1950 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - "Khushwant Singh"
    - General, 1953-2006 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - "Correspondence," 1953-1998 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - "India Prize," 1953-1999 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - "Mano Majra (Last Train to Pakistan)," 1953-1999, (2 folders) (Box 32, Folder 8-9)
    - "Original Letters," 1960-1967 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - "Spanish Civil War," 1939 1966 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Strange Victory
    - General
      - 1947 (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - "Disk 2, Disk 7," 1947-1949 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - "Assorted Reference Material," 1947 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "Chapter-Autobio," 1947-1948 1999 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - "Correspondence," 1947-1949 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - "Costs, Distribution, Finances," 1947-1950 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - "Czechoslovakia section 5e," 1948-1950 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - "Foreign," 1948-1950 1999 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - "Log," March, 1948, (2 folders) (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
    - "MISC Target Films," 1948-1950 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - "Publicity, Promotion, Release and Sale," 1947 2004 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - "Reviews, Articles, News Releases," 1948-2004, (2 folders) (Box 33, Folder 5-6)
    - "Scenario, Pre-Production Letters," 1947 1999-2004 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - "Script, Narration, Outline, Music, etc.," 1947-1948 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - "Stock footage and location requests," 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - "Stock Sources," 1947 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - "Target Films Financial," 1947-1958, (2 folders) (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
  - "Joseph Strick," 1973-1995 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - "Syracuse Lecture--Annenberg Lecture," 1990-1992 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - "Theatre of Incest--Misson," Undated (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - "Travel"
    - "Dublin," 2003, (2 folders) (Box 33, Folder 16-17)
    - "Haitian Painting," 1990-1998 (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - "India-Nepal-Goa," 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 33, Folder 19-20)
    - Miscellaneous Destinations, 1962-1989 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "Passports and Licenses," 1946-1997, (3 folders) (Box 34, Folder 2-4)
  - "Sarah Uman"
    - "Originals," 1962-1984, (2 folders) (Box 34, Folder 5-6)
    - "V. 2," 1980-1996 Undated (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "V. 3," 1996 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - "Jarlath Waldron--Excerpts from Maamtrasna," 1992 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - "Haskell Wexler--Originals," 1943-2005, (2 folders) (Box 34, Folder 10-11)
  - "War Outline, Enlistment, Rosset Writing," 1942-1949 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - "White House--Claunch," 1944-1945 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - "Rev. Wildmon"
    - "Blue Moon," 1990-2003, (2 folders) (Box 34, Folder 14-15)
    - "Boycott," 1990-1991 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - "Women's Lib"
    - "Spring Summer 1970" 1970-2001 (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - "Valerie Solanis," 1970-2002 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - "Andrew Wylie," 1985-1997 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - "Yank Magazine," 1945 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - "Quentin Young--Cook County Hospital," 1975-1981, (2 folders) (Box 35, Folder 4-5)
  - Subseries IV.1. Grove Press, 1950-2008
    Grove Press catalogs, book lists, correspondence, financial information, sales, editorial files, Authors files, print matter, business and promotional files, Random House files, and documents regarding the Grove Press Records at Syracuse University. Correspondence and related materials to Grove Press authors have been filed as in the original arrangement (some were labeled under "Authors" and others under "Correspondence"). Subseries includes Grove "Discussion Guides" providing detailed information about many of Grove's most notable titles.
    - Authors
      - "Abe-Bharti," 1970-1994, (2 folders) (Box 35, Folder 6-7)
      - "Alpert to Stuart," 1954-1998, (2 folders) (Box 35, Folder 8-9)
      - "Blake to Exner," 1967-2002 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - "Clavin to Ross," 1962-1999 Undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - "Marguerite Duras," 1959-2003 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - "Glassco-Morgan," 1962-2001 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - "Glassco-Morgan--Originals," 1960-2001 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - "Alex Haley," 1965-2010 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - "Andre Hodeir," 1966-1993 (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - "Loovis to McClure," 1977-1996 (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - "Harold Pinter"
        - "The Compartment," Undated (Box 35, Folder 18)
        - "Master," 1971-1985 (Box 35, Folder 19)
        - "Originals" 1971-2007, (2 folders) (Box 35, Folder 20-21)
      - "John Rechy," 1960-2006, (2 folders) (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
      - "Rechy--"On Being a GP Author," 1960-2006 (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - "Richie to Schultz," 1965-2002 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - "Amos Tutuola," 1953-1984 (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - "Ungerer to Zappa," 1972-2002 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - "Barney Rosset Biography/Autobiography," 1965-1969 1993 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Beat Authors
      - "Allen Ginsberg," 1978-2004 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - "Beat Conference--University of North Carolina," 2004, (2 folders) (Box 36, Folder 9-10)
        (w/ materials about Subterraneans in Italy)
      - "Beat Generation Conference, NYU," 1994 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Feltrinelli, Pivano, Kerouac, 1958-2006, (2 folders) (Box 36, Folder 12-13)
      - "Subterraneans In Italy," 1958-1995 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - "Bibliography by Author," Undated (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - "Buzz Alpert JDL Articles," 1978 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Catalogues
      - General, 1970-1986 (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - "Catalogs," 1952-1985 (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - "Catalogs," 1958-1992 (2 of 3 folders) (Box 36, Folder 19-20)
      - "Catalogs," 1958-1992 (1 of 3 folders) (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - "Catalogue," 1949-1982 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - "Catalogues--Books and Films," 1970s-1986, (2 folders) (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
      - "Educational Catalogues," 1969-1986, (2 folders) (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
      - "Film and Drama Catalogs," 1970-1975 Undated, (2 folders) (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
      - "Film Catalogs," 1969-1970s Undated, (2 folders) (Box 37, Folder 9-10)
        (w/ script for Robbe-Grillet's L'Homme qui Ment )
      - "The Grove Era: An Inventory of Grove Press (1949-1986)," 1993 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence
      - "General Correspondence"
        - "B-C," 1971-1994 (Box 37, Folder 12)
        - "C-F," 1987-1999 Undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
        - "E-I," 1961-1995 (Box 37, Folder 14)
        - "J-L, M-N," 1953-2006 (Box 37, Folder 15)
        - "S-W," 1966-2001 (Box 37, Folder 16)
      - "Assorted--Originals," 1961-1989 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 37, Folder 17)
      - "Assorted Originals," 1961-1989 (1 of 2 folders) (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - "Assorted Corresp," 1958-1998, (2 folders) (Box 38, Folder 2-3)
      - "Avedon, Ballantine, Bair, Beach, Benton," 1953-1995 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - "Barnes to Peters," 1957-1999, (2 folders) (Box 38, Folder 5-6)
      - "Fried, Gervasi, Keene, Kuntsler, Lall, Mailer," 1959-2003 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - "Richard Gallen," 1965-1997 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - "Edward de Grazia," 1951-2002, (2 folders) (Box 38, Folder 9-10)
      - "Havel, Garbus," 1975-2001 (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - "Leary, Mishima, Paz, Neruda," 1961-1982 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - "Markson to Morgan," 1968-1998 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - "Nakao to Russell," 1961-2002 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - "Charles Rembar," 1968 1999-2000 (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - "Selby, Boyle, Chamberlain, W. Shawn," 1961-1998 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - "Staff Correspondence"
        - "A-F," 1954-2001 (Box 38, Folder 17)
        - "G-M," 1957-2001 (Box 38, Folder 18)
        - "P-T," 1963-1994 (Box 38, Folder 19)
      - "Gay Talese, Hinckle," 1951-2003 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - "Tindall, Tynan, Tyler, Vidal," 1970-2004 (w/ Selby) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - "Various Corresp," 1966-1997 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "Discussion Guides," 1960s-1970s, (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 4-5)
    - "Early Grove Authors," 1951-1998 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "Editorial Files at Syracuse University," 1985-1997 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "Eugene Ionesco," 1969-1988, (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 8-9)
    - "Far Eastern Editor Related Materials," 1965-1988 Undated, (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 10-11)
    - Financial
      - "Blue Moon Financial," 1951-1990 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - "Financial Statements," 1955-2001, (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 13-14)
      - "Records--Master," 1954-1984, (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 15-16)
      - "Records--Originals," 1952-1969, (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 17-18)
      - "Records--Originals," 1970-1985 (1 of 3 folders) (Box 39, Folder 19)
      - "Records--Originals," 1970-1985 (2 of 3 folders) (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
      - "Reports," 1967-1977 2007, (2 folders) (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
      - "Stock Prospectus," 1967-1970 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - "Frankfurt Book Fair," 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "French Translations," 1952-1979 1999 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "Grove and Evergreen Authors List," 2009 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "Ionesco and Genet Correspondence," 1965-1985 (w/ letter from Robbe-Grillet) (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Marnia Lazreg," 1971-2003 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Legal Files
      - General, 2002 (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - "FLM Joint Board Union Arbitration," 1970, (2 folders) (Box 40, Folder 12-13)
      - "Molloy Court Case," 1986-1989 (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - "Rosset, Grove, Evergreen legal cases," 1969-2005 (Box 40, Folder 15)
      - "Union/FLM vs Grove Press," 1970 (Box 40, Folder 16)
      - "Women's Lib Furrier's Union Arbitration," 1970, (2 folders) (Box 40, Folder 17-18)
    - "List of Rosset Correspondence," 1996 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962-2001, (2 folders) (Box 40, Folder 20-21)
    - "Nami Mun," 2002-2009 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - "Order Forms," 1971-1973 1985-1986 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - "Random House"
      - General, 1972-1986 (Box 40, Folder 24)
      - "Distribution," 1974-1978 (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - "Publishing, Catalogs, Fact Sheets-Volume I," 1973-1985, (2 folders) (Box 41, Folder 2-3)
      - "Publishing, Catalogs, Fact Sheets-Volume II," 1974 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - "Rosset Ouster"
      - Binder 1, 1985-2005, (2 folders) (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
      - Binder 2, 1985-1994, (2 folders) (Box 41, Folder 7-8)
      - "Deposition I, II, III," 1986 2007, (2 folders) (Box 41, Folder 9-10)
      - "Ann Getty Corespondence," 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - "Peter Getty," 1984-1986 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - "Rosset against Getty, Weidenfeld"
        - General, 1986-1992 (Box 41, Folder 13)
        - "Deposition I," 1986 (Box 41, Folder 14)
        - "Deposition II," 1986 (Box 41, Folder 15)
        - Legal Documents, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 41, Folder 16-17)
      - "Stock Purchase Agreement, Getty-Rosset," 1985 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - "Sales," 1985-1986 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - "Selected Letters," 1966-2000, (2 folders) (Box 42, Folder 3-4)
    - "Syracuse University Correspondence and Accession Forms," 1971-1993 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - "Titles," 1949-1985 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Waiting for Godot /Steve McQueen, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Sub-subseries IV.1.1. Grove Film, 1950-2008
      Pamphlets, catalogs, distribution and promotional materials, and correspondence pertaining to the Grove Press Film Festivals, Evergreen Film and Video projects, as well as original or adapted screenplays by Rosset and others such as Alain Robbe-Grillet and Eugene Ionesco.
      - "AAUN and Cowan Film Project," 1950-1951 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - "Beyond Books" Film Production and Distribution at the Grove Press Publishing House," 2008 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - "Francis Ford Coppola," 1973-1995 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - "Creative Film Foundation," 1954-1956 (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - "Digital Film Budget," 2003-2005 (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - "Evergreen Club News," Undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - "Evergreen Theater E.H.," 1959-1960 (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - "The Ferlinghetti Story" Screenplay, Undated (Box 42, Folder 15)
      - "Film Distribution"
        - "1,"1964-1975 (Box 42, Folder 16)
        - "2," 1974-1994 (Box 42, Folder 17)
        - "3," 1950 1980-1986 (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - "Film Distribution Video Magazine," 1967 (Box 42, Folder 19)
      - "Film Project," 1950 (Box 42, Folder 20)
      - "Film Tributes," 1971-1973 (Box 42, Folder 21)
      - "Films," 1968 2005 Undated (Box 42, Folder 22)
      - "Genet Film Ordering Info," 2003 (Box 42, Folder 23)
      - "Girl Beneath the Lion," 1976 (Box 42, Folder 24)
      - "Jean-Luc Godard," 1970 Undated (Box 42, Folder 25)
      - "George Grosz," 1960-1966 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - "I am Curious Yellow," 1968-1982 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - "Eugene Ionesco--The Hard-Boiled Egg," 2002-2006 Undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - "Media Reports on Grove Film," 1963-1992 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - "MOMA Film Program," 2006 (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - "OBSCENE Corr. & Agreement," 2003-2007 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - "Quiet Days in Clichy," 1970-1971 2005 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - "Robbe-Grillet Frank's Return Film Scenario," Undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - "Vilgot Sjoman," 1990-2003 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      - "François Truffaut," 1974 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      - "Howard Turner--Originals," 1953-1967, (2 folders) (Box 43, Folder 11-12)
      - "Video Specials," 1974-1982 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      - "The Wanderer" Film Script," 1941-1950 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Subseries IV.2. Interviews and Articles, 1953-2006
    Transcripts, printouts, and correspondence of interviews involving Barney Rosset, and published articles related to Rosset. The original arrangement lead to some duplication of materials that were given different titles.
    - "7 Days--Barney Rosset's Erotica," 1989 (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - "Alexander Lawrence Interview," 1997 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - "Arafat-Schleifer, Ev. Rev.," 1968 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - "Articles," 1986-1999 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - "Articles about Barney Rosset--MANY," 1968-2000, (3 folders) (Box 43, Folder 19-21)
    - "Barney Rosset and The Art of Combat Publishing by John Oakes," 1982-1985 (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - "Brooklyn Rail-Lockwood, Walsh & Rosset," 2000 (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - "Contemporary Authors," 1979-1980 (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - "Dictionary of Literary Biography Yearbook," 2002 (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - "East Hampton Star, 1995-1998 (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - "Edelstein and Finley Interviews," 2000-2004 Undated (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - "Geller Interview and Rosset-Turner," 1987 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - "Geller-Rosset, Calder," 1987 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - "Getty-Weidenfeld articles," 1986-1990 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - "Gold/Rosset, DLB/Rosset," 1997 2002 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - "Gontarski--B.R.'s Strange Victory--Irish Journal," 1999 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "Gontarski Grove Legacy," 1990-2000 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Index on Censorship Interview," 1987-1989 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "Index on Censorship-Rosset," 1987 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - "International Herald Tribune," 1998 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - "International Virus Vol 1, Issue 1," 1995 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - "Internet Articles," 1989-2001 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Interviews by Edward DeGrazia
      - General, 2004 Undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - "DeGrazia Interviews," 1981-1983 (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - "Edward DeGrazia with Barney Rosset," Undated (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - "Ed DeGrazia with Wexler, Adler, Mitchell, Young," Undated (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - 'Interview, Dairy Aire, Swarthmore, Magnificent Maverick," 1990s-2000s (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - "Interview--Grove History," 2002 Undated (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - "Interview Janos Gat Gallery for CUNY TV," 2002 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - "Irish America Magazine," 1995 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - "Jerry Gold-Rosset (Black Heron)," 1997-2001 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - "John Oakes Interview," 1982 Undated (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - "Ken Jordan-Rosset--Paris Review," 1996 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - "Mary Beth Hinton-Rosset (Syracuse)," 1993 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - "McCormick (Tin House)-Rosset," 2001 (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - "Sandy Meehan Tapes"
      - "No. 1, 2, 3," 2003-2004, (3 folders) (Box 44, Folder 25-27)
      - "Rosset Lecture moderated by Meehan," 2004 (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - Mike Golden & Barney Pieces, 1989-1990 (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - "Mike Top Book Forum," 2006 (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1970-1999 (Box 44, Folder 31)
      - "Disk 58 Originals," 1953-1985 (Box 44, Folder 32)
      - "Disk 81," 1968-2001, (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
    - "MPH Entertainment & Rosset," 2000 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "The New Positivist-Rosset," 1994 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "Niles Southern Interview," 2004 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - "No Source--Rosset-Seaver," 1990 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - "Paris Review--Originals," 1993-1996 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "Review of Contemporary Fiction," 1990 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - "Rosset by Hinton-Syracuse," 1974-1975 1990-1993 2007 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - "Rosset/Edelstein Interview--Pataphysics," 2006 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "Rosset & Finley," Undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "Rosset Interview with Mark Wexler," 2004-2005 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - "Rosset-Southgate Interview," 1990, (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 13-14)
    - "Screw Magazine" and others, 1970-1999 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - "Southgate Interviews," 1990-1998 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - "Stieber-Rosset New York Quarterly," 1995 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - "Wall Street Journal Europe," 2004 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - "Women's Lib Takeover of Grove--Mike Golden" Undated (Box 45, Folder 19)
- Series V: Samuel Beckett Material, 1935-2007
  This series gathers materials related to the Nobel Prize-winning Irish writer, Samuel Beckett, such as correspondence, writings, photographs, and print matter. It has been further arranged into two sub-series, Correspondence and Beckett-related materials, affairs, and projects.
  - Subseries V.1: Correspondence, 1953-2005
    Photocopies, transcriptions, with some originals of the correspondence between Samuel Beckett and Barney Rosset. This series also contains correspondence by Beckett sent to other recipients than Rosset, including French letters, as well as files related to an edition of selected letters between Beckett and Rosset by Stan Gontarski.
    - "Beckett by BR--Letters--Centre Pompidou," 1962 1986-1995 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - “Beckett-Grove--Beckett to Schmidt, 1957” (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - "Beckett Letters to Joseph Chaikin," 1980-1985 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - “Beckett Letters--Schmidt, Others,” 1969-1971 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - “Beckett-Rosset Correspondence”
      - “1953-1956” (Box 45, Folder 24)
      - "1953-1956" (different binder) (Box 45, Folder 25)
      - “1954” (with Edits) (Box 45, Folder 26)
      - “1955-1956” (with Edits) (Box 45, Folder 27)
      - “1956-1957” (Box 45, Folder 28)
      - “1957” (Box 45, Folder 29)
      - “1957-1959” (Box 45, Folder 30)
      - "1957-1966", (2 folders) (Box 45, Folder 31-32)
      - "1960-1961" (Box 45, Folder 33)
      - “1960-1964” (Box 45, Folder 34)
      - “1962-1964” (Box 45, Folder 35)
      - “1964-1967--Originals”, (2 folders) (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
      - "1968-1969" (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - “1969-1971” (Box 46, Folder 4)
      - "1969-1979", (2 folders) (Box 46, Folder 5-6)
      - “1970s & 1980s” (Box 46, Folder 7)
      - “1980s”, (2 folders) (Box 46, Folder 8-9)
      - “1980-1987” (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - "Cables from Rosset," 1985-1989 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      - “Copies of Originals”
        - 1953 1954 1955 (Box 46, Folder 12)
        - 1953-1956, (3 folders) (Box 46, Folder 13-15)
        - 1957 (Box 46, Folder 16)
        - 1958 (Box 46, Folder 17)
        - 1959 (Box 46, Folder 18)
        - 1960-1961 (Box 46, Folder 19-20)
      - Gontarski
        - “1953 1954 1955” (Box 47, Folder 1)
        - “1953-1959”, (3 folders) (Box 47, Folder 2-4)
        - 1953-1972, (2 folders) (Box 47, Folder 5-6)
        - “1957-1959” (Box 47, Folder 7)
        - “1959-1963” 1959-1982, (2 folders) (Box 47, Folder 8-9)